<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<article lang="en" id="index">
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Icon Naming Specification</title>
    <releaseinfo>Version 0.8.90</releaseinfo>
    <date>August 9 2007</date>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
	<firstname>Rodney</firstname>
	<surname>Dawes</surname>
	<affiliation>
	  <address>
	    <email>dobey.pwns@gmail.com</email>
	  </address>
	</affiliation>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="overview">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>
The Icon Theme Specification has been in use now for a while, in several
desktops, including KDE and Gnome. However, there has never been any
centralized direction on how to name the icons that are available for use
by applications, when creating a theme. This has meant that artists have
historically had to duplicate many icons, in order for their themes to
work across desktop environments.
    </para>
    <para>
This specification aims to solve this problem, by laying out a standard
naming scheme for icon creation, as well as providing a minimal list of
must have icons. Addendums to this specification will provide additional
icon lists for extended sets, such as devices and MIME types.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="context">
    <title>Context</title>

    <para>
      The list of default Contexts for the icon theme are:
    </para>

    <table>
      <title>Standard Contexts</title>

      <tgroup cols="3">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	    <entry>Directory</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Actions</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons which are generally used in menus and dialogs for
interacting with the user.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>actions</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Animations</entry>
	    <entry>
Animated images used to represent loading web sites, or other
background processing which may be less suited to more verbose
progress reporting in the user interface. Animations should be a PNG with
frames which are the size of the directory the animation is in, tiled in a
WxH grid. Implementations should determine the number of frames by dividing
the image into its frames, and iterating from left to right, wrapping to the
first frame, after rendering the last.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>animations</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Applications</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons that describe what an application is, for use in the
Programs menu, window decorations, and the task list. These may
or may not be generic depending on the application and its
purpose. Applications which are to be considered part of the base desktop,
such as the calculator or terminal, should use the generic icons specified in
this specification, while more advanced applications such as web browsers and
office applications should use branded icons which still give the user an idea
of what function the application provides.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>apps</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Categories</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons that are used for categories in the Programs menu, or
the Control Center, for separating applications, preferences, and
settings for display to the user.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>categories</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Devices</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons for hardware that is contained within or connected to the
computing device. Naming for extended devices in this group, is of the form
&lt;primary function&gt;-&lt;manufacturer&gt;-&lt;model&gt;. This allows ease
of fallback to the primary function device name, or ones more targeted for
a specific series of models from a manufacturer. For example, a theme author
may want to provide icons for different phones. The specific model icons could
be named <quote>phone-samsung-t809</quote>, <quote>phone-motorola-rokr</quote>,
and <quote>phone-motorola-pebl</quote>. However, the theme must provide a phone
icon in the theme's style, so that devices not matching these models, will
still have an appropriate icon. An exception to this rule is that the
<quote>media</quote> icons do not need to include manufacturer names, as they
are generic items, and may be available from many manufacturers. As a result,
for media, the specific icons are to differentiate between different specific
types of media. For exmaple, an artist may wish to provide icons for BluRay,
DVD, HD-DVD, CD-ROM, and variations thereof. The specific media type icons
should be named in the form, &lt;primary function&gt;-&lt;specific format&gt;.
Some examples are <quote>media-optical</quote>, <quote>media-optical-bd</quote>
and <quote>media-optical-dvd</quote>.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>devices</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Emblems</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons for tags and properties of files, that are displayed in the
file manager. This context contains emblems for such things as
<quote>read-only</quote> or <quote>photos</quote>.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>emblems</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Emotes</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons for emotions that are expressed through text chat
applications such as :-) or :-P in IRC or instant messengers.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>emotes</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>International</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons for international denominations such as flags.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>intl</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>MimeTypes</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons for different types of data, such as audio or image files.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>mimetypes</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Places</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons used to represent locations, either on the local
filesystem, or through remote connections. Folders, trash, and
workgroups are some examples.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>places</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Status</entry>
	    <entry>
Icons for presenting status to the user. This context contains
icons for warning and error dialogs, as well as for the current
weather, appointment alarms, and battery status.
	    </entry>
	    <entry>status</entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="guidelines">
    <title>Icon Naming Guidelines</title>

    <para>
Here we define some guidelines for when creating new icons that extend
the standardized list of icon names defined here, in order to provide
icons for more specific MIME types, devices, or international flags.
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
Icon names are in the en_US.US_ASCII locale. This means that the
allowable characters in the icon names, must fall withing the
US-ASCII character set. As a further restriction, all icon names
may only contain lowercase letters, numbers, underscore, dash, or
period characters. Spaces, colons, slashes, and backslashes are
not allowed. Also, icon names must be spelled as they are in the
en_US dictionary.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
The dash <quote>-</quote> character is used to separate levels of
specificity in icon names, for all contexts other than MimeTypes.
For instance, we use <quote>input-mouse</quote> as the generic
item for all mouse devices, and we use <quote>input-mouse-usb</quote>
for a USB mouse device. However, if the more specific item does not exist
in the current theme, and does exist in a parent theme, the generic icon
from the current theme is preferred, in order to keep consistent style.
	  </para>
	  <para>
The <quote>Applications</quote> context should not use this method of
falling back to more generic icons. An application must either use a
generic application icon name provided by this specification, or install
an icon named the same as the executable for running the application. A
generic desktop application included with the desktop suite, such as the
calculator or terminal application, should use the generic names provided
by this specification, as described above in the <quote>Applications</quote>
context description.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="names">
    <title>Standard Icon Names</title>

    <para>
This section describes the standard icon names that should be used by
artists when creating themes, and by developers when writing applications
which will use the Icon Theme Specification.
    </para>

    <table id="actions">
      <title>Standard Action Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>address-book-new</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the action to create a new address book.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>application-exit</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for exiting an application. Typically this is seen
in the application's menus as File-&gt;Quit.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>appointment-new</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the action to create a new appointment
in a calendaring application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>call-start</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for initiating or accepting a call. Should be similar
to the standard cellular call pickup icon, a green handset with ear and
mouth pieces facing upward.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>call-stop</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for stopping a current call. Should be similar
to the standard cellular call hangup icon, a red handset with ear and
mouth pieces facing downward.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>contact-new</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the action to create a new contact
in an address book application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-new</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the action to create a new document.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-open</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the action to open a document.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-open-recent</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the action to open a document that
was recently opened.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-page-setup</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the page setup action of a document editor.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-print</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the print action of an application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-print-preview</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the print preview action of an application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-properties</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the action to view the properties of a
document in an application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-revert</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the action of reverting to a previous
version of a document.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-save</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the save action. Should be an arrow pointing down and toward
a hard disk.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-save-as</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the save as action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>document-send</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the send action. Should be an arrow pointing up and away from
a hard disk.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-clear</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the clear action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-copy</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the copy action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-cut</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the cut action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-delete</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the delete action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-find</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the find action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-find-replace</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the find and replace action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-paste</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the paste action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-redo</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the redo action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-select-all</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the select all action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>edit-undo</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the undo action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>find-location</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the action of finding the user's physical location
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>folder-new</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for creating a new folder.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-indent-less</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the decrease indent formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-indent-more</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the increase indent formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-justify-center</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the center justification formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-justify-fill</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the fill justification formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-justify-left</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the left justification formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-justify-right</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the right justification action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-text-direction-ltr</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the left-to-right text formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-text-direction-rtl</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the right-to-left formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-text-bold</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the bold text formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-text-italic</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the italic text formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-text-underline</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the underlined text formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>format-text-strikethrough</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the strikethrough text formatting action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-bottom</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go to bottom of a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-down</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go down in a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-first</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go to the first item in a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-home</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go to home location action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-jump</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the jump to action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-last</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go to the last item in a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-next</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go to the next item in a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-previous</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go to the previous item in a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-top</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go to the top of a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>go-up</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the go up in a list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>help-about</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the About item in the Help menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>help-contents</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for Contents item in the Help menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>help-faq</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the FAQ item in the Help menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>insert-image</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the insert image action of an application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>insert-link</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the insert link action of an application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>insert-object</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the insert object action of an application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>insert-text</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the insert text action of an application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>list-add</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the add to list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>list-remove</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the remove from list action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-forward</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the forward action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-mark-important</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the mark as important action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-mark-junk</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the mark as junk action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-mark-notjunk</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the mark as not junk action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-mark-read</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the mark as read action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-mark-unread</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the mark as unread action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-message-new</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the compose new mail action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-reply-all</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the reply to all action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-reply-sender</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the reply to sender action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-send</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the send action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-send-receive</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the send and receive action of an electronic mail application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-eject</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the eject action of a media player or file manager.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-playback-pause</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the pause action of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-playback-start</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the start playback action of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-playback-stop</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the stop action of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-record</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the record action of a media application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-seek-backward</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the seek backward action of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-seek-forward</entry>
            <entry>
The icon for the seek forward action of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-skip-backward</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the skip backward action of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-skip-forward</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the skip forward action of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>object-flip-horizontal</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the action to flip an object horizontally.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>object-flip-vertical</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the action to flip an object vertically.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>object-rotate-left</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the rotate left action performed on an object.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>object-rotate-right</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the rotate rigt action performed on an object.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
          <row>
            <entry>process-stop</entry>
            <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Stop</quote> action in applications with actions
that may take a while to process, such as web page loading in a browser.
            </entry>
          </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-lock-screen</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Lock Screen</quote> item in the desktop's
panel application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-log-out</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Log Out</quote> item in
the desktop's panel application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-run</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Run Application...</quote> item in
the desktop's panel application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-search</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Search</quote> item in
the desktop's panel application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
          <row>
            <entry>system-reboot</entry>
            <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Reboot</quote> item in
the desktop's panel application.
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>system-shutdown</entry>
            <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Shutdown</quote> item in
the desktop's panel application.
            </entry>
          </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>tools-check-spelling</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Check Spelling</quote> item in the
application's <quote>Tools</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>view-fullscreen</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Fullscreen</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>view-refresh</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Refresh</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>view-restore</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used by an application for leaving the fullscreen view, and returning
to a normal windowed view.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>view-sort-ascending</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Sort Ascending</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu, or in a button for
changing the sort method for a list.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>view-sort-descending</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Sort Descending</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu, or in a button for
changing the sort method for a list.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>window-close</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Close Window</quote> item in the
application's <quote>Windows</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>window-new</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>New Window</quote> item in the
application's <quote>Windows</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>zoom-fit-best</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Best Fit</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>zoom-in</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Zoom in</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>zoom-original</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Original Size</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>zoom-out</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the <quote>Zoom Out</quote> item in the
application's <quote>View</quote> menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="animations">
      <title>Standard Animation Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>process-working</entry>
	    <entry>
This is the standard spinner animation for web browsers and
file managers to show that the location is loading.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="apps">
      <title>Standard Application Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>accessories-calculator</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's calculator accessory program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>accessories-character-map</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's international and extended text
character accessory program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>accessories-dictionary</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's dictionary accessory program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>accessories-screenshot-tool</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's screenshot taking program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>accessories-text-editor</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's text editing accessory program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>help-browser</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's help browsing application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>multimedia-volume-control</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's hardware volume control application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-accessibility</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's accessibility preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-font</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's font preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-keyboard</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's keyboard preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-locale</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's locale preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-multimedia</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's multimedia preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-screensaver</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's screen saving preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-theme</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's theme preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-wallpaper</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's wallpaper preferences.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-file-manager</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's file management application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-software-install</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's software installer application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-software-update</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's software updating application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>utilities-system-monitor</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's system resource monitor application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>utilities-terminal</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the desktop's terminal emulation application.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="categories">
      <title>Standard Category Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-accessories</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Accessories</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-development</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Programming</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-engineering</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Engineering</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-games</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Games</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-graphics</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Graphics</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-internet</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Internet</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-multimedia</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Multimedia</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-office</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Office</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-other</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Other</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-science</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Science</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-system</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>System Tools</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>applications-utilities</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Utilities</quote> sub-menu of the Programs menu.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Desktop Preferences</quote> category.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-peripherals</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Peripherals</quote> sub-category of
the <quote>Desktop Preferences</quote> category.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-desktop-personal</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Personal</quote> sub-category of
the <quote>Desktop Preferences</quote> category.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-other</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Other</quote> preferences category.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-system</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>System Preferences</quote> category.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>preferences-system-network</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Network</quote> sub-category of
the <quote>System Preferences</quote> category.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>system-help</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Help</quote> system category.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="devices">
      <title>Standard Device Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>audio-card</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the audio rendering device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>audio-input-microphone</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the microphone audio input device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>battery</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the system battery device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>camera-photo</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for a digital still camera devices.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>camera-video</entry>
	    <entry>
The fallback icon for video cameras.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>camera-web</entry>
	    <entry>
The fallback icon for web cameras.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>computer</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the computing device as a whole.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>drive-harddisk</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for hard disk drives.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>drive-optical</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for optical media drives such as CD and DVD.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>drive-removable-media</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for removable media drives.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>input-gaming</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the gaming input device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>input-keyboard</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the keyboard input device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>input-mouse</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the mousing input device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>input-tablet</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for graphics tablet input devices.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-flash</entry>
	    <entry>
The fallback icon used for flash media, such as memory stick and SD.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-floppy</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for physical floppy disk media.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-optical</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for physical optical media such as CD and DVD.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-tape</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic physical tape media.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>modem</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for modem devices.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>multimedia-player</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic multimedia playing devices.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>network-wired</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for wired network connections.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>network-wireless</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for wireless network connections.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>pda</entry>
	    <entry>
This is the fallback icon for Personal Digial Assistant devices. Primary use
of this icon is for PDA devices connected to the PC. Connection medium is not
an important aspect of the icon. The metaphor for this fallback icon should be
a generic PDA device icon.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>phone</entry>
	    <entry>
This is the default fallback for phone devices. Primary use of this icon group
is for phone devices which support connectivity to the PC. These may be VoIP,
cellular, or possibly landline phones. The metaphor for this fallback should be
a generic mobile phone device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>printer</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for a printer device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>scanner</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for a scanner device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>video-display</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the monitor that video gets displayed to.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="emblems">
      <title>Standard Emblem Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-default</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem to specify the default selection of a printer for
example.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-documents</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for the directory where a user's documents are stored.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-downloads</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for the directory where a user's
downloads from the internet are stored.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-favorite</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for files and directories that the
user marks as favorites.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-important</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for files and directories that are
marked as important by the user.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-mail</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem to specify the directory where the
user's electronic mail is stored.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-photos</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem to specify the directory where the
user stores photographs.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-readonly</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for files and directories which can
not be written to by the user.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-shared</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for files and directories that are
shared to other users.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-symbolic-link</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for files and direcotires that are
links to other files or directories on the filesystem.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-synchronized</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for files or directories that are
configured to be synchronized to another device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-system</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for directories that contain system
libraries, settings, and data.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>emblem-unreadable</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used as an emblem for files and directories that are inaccessible.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="emotes">
      <title>Standard Emotion Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-angel</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the 0:-) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-angry</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the X-( emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-cool</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the B-) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-crying</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :'( emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-devilish</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the &gt;:-) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-embarrassed</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-[ emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-kiss</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-* emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-laugh</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-)) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-monkey</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-(|) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-plain</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-| emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-raspberry</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-P emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-sad</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-( emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-sick</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-&amp; emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-smile</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-smile-big</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-D emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-smirk</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-! emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-surprise</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-0 emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-tired</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the |-) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-uncertain</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-/ emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-wink</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the ;-) emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>face-worried</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for the :-S emote.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="intl">
      <title>Standard International Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>flag-aa</entry>
	    <entry>
The flag for the country with the ISO 3166 country code AA. All
flags should use ISO 3166 two-letter country codes, in lowercase
form, as the specifier for the country.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="mimetypes">
      <title>Standard MIME Type Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>application-x-executable</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for executable file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>audio-x-generic</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic audio file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>font-x-generic</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic font file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>image-x-generic</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic image file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>package-x-generic</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic package file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>text-html</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for HTML text file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>text-x-generic</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic text file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>text-x-generic-template</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic text templates.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>text-x-script</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for script file types, such as shell scripts.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>video-x-generic</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic video file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>x-office-address-book</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic address book file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>x-office-calendar</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic calendar file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>x-office-document</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic document and letter file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>x-office-presentation</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic presentation file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>x-office-spreadsheet</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for generic spreadsheet file types.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="places">
      <title>Standard Place Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>folder</entry>
	    <entry>
The standard folder icon used to represent directories on local
filesystems, mail folders, and other hierarchical groups.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>folder-remote</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for normal directories on a remote filesystem.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>network-server</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for individual host machines under the
<quote>Network Servers</quote> place in the file manager.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>network-workgroup</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the <quote>Network Servers</quote> place in the
desktop's file manager, and workgroups within the network.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>start-here</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used by the desktop's main menu for accessing places,
applications, and other features.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-bookmarks</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the user's special <quote>Bookmarks</quote> place.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-desktop</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the special <quote>Desktop</quote> directory of the user.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-home</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the special <quote>Home</quote> directory of the user.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-trash</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the user's <quote>Trash</quote> place in the
desktop's file manager.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <table id="status">
      <title>Standard Status Icons</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Name</entry>
	    <entry>Description</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>appointment-missed</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when an appointment was missed.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>appointment-soon</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when an appointment will occur soon.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>audio-volume-high</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used to indicate high audio volume.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>audio-volume-low</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used to indicate low audio volume.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>audio-volume-medium</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used to indicate medium audio volume.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>audio-volume-muted</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used to indicate the muted state for audio playback.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>battery-caution</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when the battery is below 40%.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>battery-low</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when the battery is below 20%.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>dialog-error</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a dialog is opened to explain an error
condition to the user.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>dialog-information</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a dialog is opened to give information
to the user that may be pertinent to the requested action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>dialog-password</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a dialog requesting the authentication
credentials for a user is opened.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>dialog-question</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a dialog is opened to ask a simple
	      question of the user.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>dialog-warning</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a dialog is opened to warn the user of
impending issues with the requested action.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>folder-drag-accept</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for a folder while an object is being
dragged onto it, that is of a type that the directory can contain.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>folder-open</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for folders, while their contents are being
displayed within the same window. This icon would normally be
shown in a tree or list view, next to the main view of a folder's contents.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>folder-visiting</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for folders, while their contents are being
displayed in another window. This icon would typically be used
when using multiple windows to navigate the hierarchy, such as
in Nautilus's spatial mode.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>image-loading</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when another image is being loaded, such as
thumnails for larger images in the file manager.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>image-missing</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when another image could not be loaded.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-attachment</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for an electronic mail that contains attachments.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-unread</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for an electronic mail that is unread.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-read</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for an electronic mail that is read.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-replied</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for an electronic mail that has been replied to.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-signed</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for an electronic mail that contains a signature.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>mail-signed-verified</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used for an electronic mail that contains a signature
which has also been verified by the security system.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-playlist-repeat</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the repeat mode of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>media-playlist-shuffle</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the shuffle mode of a media player.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>network-error</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when an error occurs trying to intialize the network connection
of the computing device. This icon should be two computers, one in the
background, with the screens of both computers, colored black, and with the
theme's style element for errors, overlayed on top of the icon.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
          <row>
            <entry>network-idle</entry>
            <entry>
The icon used when no data is being transmitted or received, while the
computing device is connected to a network. This icon should be two computers,
one in the background, with the screens of both computers, colored black.
            </entry>
          </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>network-offline</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when the computing device is disconnected from the network. This
icon should be a computer in the background, with a screen colored black, and
the theme's icon element to show that a device is not accessible, in the
foreground.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
          <row>
            <entry>network-receive</entry>
            <entry>
The icon used when data is being received, while the computing device is
connected to a network. This icon should be two computers, one in the
background, with its screen colored green, and the screen of the computer in
the foreground, colored black.
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>network-transmit</entry>
            <entry>
The icon used when data is being transmitted, while the computing device is
connected to a network. This icon should be two computers, one in the
background, with its screen colored black, and the screen of the computer in
the foreground, colored green.

            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>network-transmit-receive</entry>
            <entry>
The icon used data is being both transmitted and received simultaneously,
while the computing device is connected to a network. This icon should be two
computers, one in the background, with the screens of both computers, colored
green.
            </entry>
          </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>printer-error</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when an error occurs while attempting to print. This icon should
be the theme's printer device icon, with the theme's style element for errors,
overlayed on top of the icon.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>printer-printing</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while a print job is successfully being spooled to a printing
device. This icon should be the theme's printer device icon, with a document
emerging from the printing device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>security-high</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used to indicate that the security level of a connection is known
to be secure, using strong encryption and a valid certificate.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>security-medium</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used to indicate that the security level of a connection is presumed
to be secure, using strong encryption, and a certificate that could not be
automatically verified, but which the user has chosen to trust.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>security-low</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used to indicate that the security level of a connection is presumed
to be insecure, either by using weak encryption, or by using a certificate that
the could not be automatically verified, and which the user has not chosent to
trust.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>software-update-available</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when an update is available for software installed
on the computing device, through the system software update program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>software-update-urgent</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when an urgent update is available through the
system software update program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>sync-error</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when an error occurs while attempting to
synchronize data from the computing device, to another device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>sync-synchronizing</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while data is successfully synchronizing to another device.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>task-due</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a task is due soon.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>task-past-due</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a task that was due, has been left incomplete.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
    <row>
      <entry>user-available</entry>
      <entry>
The icon used when a user on a chat network is available to
initiate a conversation with.
      </entry>
    </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-away</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a user on a chat network is away from their
keyboard and the chat program.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-idle</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a user on a chat network has not been an
active participant in any chats on the network, for an extended period of time.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-offline</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used when a user on a chat network is not available.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>user-trash-full</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon for the user's <quote>Trash</quote> in the desktop's
file manager, when there are items in the <quote>Trash</quote>
waiting for disposal or recovery.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-clear</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while the weather for a region is <quote>clear skies</quote>.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-clear-night</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while the weather for a region is <quote>clear skies</quote>
during the night.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-few-clouds</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while the weather for a region is <quote>partly cloudy</quote>.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-few-clouds-night</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while the weather for a region is <quote>partly cloudy</quote>
during the night.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-fog</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while the weather for a region is <quote>foggy</quote>.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-overcast</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while the weather for a region is <quote>overcast</quote>.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-severe-alert</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while a sever weather alert is in effect for a region.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-showers</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while rain showers are occurring in a region.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-showers-scattered</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while scattered rain showers are occurring in a region.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-snow</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while snow showers are occurring in a region.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>weather-storm</entry>
	    <entry>
The icon used while storms are occurring in a region.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

  </sect1>

  <appendix id="changelog">
    <title>Change History</title>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.8, 1 August 2006, Rodney Dawes</title>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "view-restore" and "utilities-system-monitor"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "folder-new" and "mail-send"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "object-flip-horizontal" and "object-flip-vertical"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "object-rotate-left" and "object-rotate-right"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "applications-engineering" and "applications-science"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Remove duplicate "preferences-desktop-accessibility"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Rename "drive-cdrom" to "drive-optical"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Rename "media-cdrom" to "media-optical"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "media-flash", "media-tape", and "modem"</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "security-high", "security-medium", and "security-low"</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.7, 15 February 2006, Rodney Dawes</title>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Remove the wallpaper-* icon names</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Align text blocks to the left</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "weather-few-clouds-night" and "weather-clear-night" to
the status context</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Remove "network-online" from the status context</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add "network-idle", "network-receive", "network-transmit",
and "network-transmit-receive" to the status context</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Update the printer status icon definitions</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.6, 07 December 2005, Rodney Dawes</title>
      <para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Add the "Animations" and "Places" contexts
	    </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Add "media-eject" to the actions context
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Move "media-playlist-shuffle" to the status context
            </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Add the "process-working" animation to the animations context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Add "battery", "camera-photo", "media-floppy", "multimedia-player",
              "network-wired", and "network-wireless" to the devices context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Remove the printer-remote and video-card icons from devices
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Rename "emblem-favorites" to "emblem-favorite"
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Add "application-x-executable", "package-x-generic",
              "text-x-generic-template", and "text-x-script" to the
              mimetypes context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Rename "x-directory-normal" to "folder" and move it to the
              places context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Rename "x-directory-remote" to "folder-remote" and move it to the
              places context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Rename "x-directory-normal-remote-server" to "network-server"
              and move it to the places context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Rename "x-directory-normal-remote-workgroup" to
              "network-workgroup" and move it to the places context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Rename "x-directory-trash" to "user-trash"
              and move it to the places context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Rename "x-directory-trash-full" to "user-trash-full" and move
              it to the status context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Add "start-here", "user-desktop", and "user-home" to the places
              context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Add "folder-drag-accept", "folder-open", "folder-visiting", and
              "media-playlist-repeat" to the status context
	    </para>
          </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.4, 10 October 2005, Rodney Dawes</title>
      <para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Use "The icon" instead of "This icon" for "contact-new" and
              "battery-low"
	    </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Add icons for "preferences-desktop-accessibility" and
              "preferences-desktop-font" in the apps context
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Fix typo in "drive-cdrom" name
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Rename "x-font-generic" to "font-x-generic" to match other MIME
              type icons such as for audio, images, and video
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Add icons for "image-loading" and "image-missing" to status
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.3, 28 June 2005, Rodney Dawes</title>
      <para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Replace "printer-local" with "printer" to be more generic.
	    </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Import into freedesktop.org cvs alongside icon-theme-spec.xml
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Add missing icon descriptions.
            </para>
          </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.2, 01 April 2005, Jakub Steiner</title>
      <para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Fixed two small typographical errors.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
    <formalpara>
      <title>Version 0.1, 29 March 2005, Rodney Dawes</title>
      <para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Created initial draft.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </formalpara>
  </appendix>
</article>
